<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-28T23:35:09-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Will’s Travlelog</title><subtitle>Capturing the trips and adventures we are lucky to have.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/02/28/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2023-02-28T20:29:51-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-28T20:29:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/02/28/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/02/28/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Winter Vacation 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/ski/snowboard/france/switzerland/2023/02/26/winter-vacation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Vacation 2023" /><published>2023-02-26T20:29:51-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T20:29:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/ski/snowboard/france/switzerland/2023/02/26/winter-vacation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/ski/snowboard/france/switzerland/2023/02/26/winter-vacation.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0114.jpeg" alt="Winter Vacation 2023" /></p>

<h2 id="day-1--2">Day 1 &amp; 2</h2>
<h3 id="travel-days">Travel Days</h3>

<p>We have a hectic day today. Séamus has two hockey games (at 11 and 1:10) before we head to Logan airport. We grab pizza at Santarpio’s before boarding our Aer Lingus flight to Dublin. Séamus and I watch Bullet Train while Orla watches Little Women. We get some sleep on an uneventful flight. Dublin is a busy airport but we do not need to do passport control here because we are just connecting. We grab some breakfast quickly and jump on our connector to Geneva. The sun is not up in Ireland yet but it is close.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0523.jpeg" style="max-width:800px;width:100%" /></p>

<p>We land in Geneva and make our way to passport control. We get through quickly and grab our bags. After checking in with AlpyBus about our transfer we have about 30m to burn.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0014.jpeg" alt="airport" /></p>

<p>A couple of hour later and have napping on the bus we arrive in Morzine. Our apartment is nice. Plenty of room, well equipped, and cozy. With some great views.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0079.jpeg" alt="apartment" /></p>

<p>After settling in we are now hungry and need to pick up something’s in town. We walk for about 10 minutes to the Pleany area and crab a bite to eat at Bistro de montagne La Cendrée.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0017.jpeg" alt="dinner" /></p>

<p>The weather is beautiful. Great sun on our backs as we relax with some local fare.</p>

<p>Next, we pick up our ski passes for the week and head to the local Spar to get some provisions for the week. We buy a reusable bag, we like collecting them as souvaneers from our trips.</p>

<p>On the way back Séamus and Orla rest their skis from Felix Ski. The staff there are friendly and we get a discount from our accommodation (they asked where we were staying and point this out). We are able to keep our equipment in their store nightly so we do not have to lug it back to the apartment.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0022.jpeg" alt="skis" /></p>

<p>As the sun sets we head back to our apartment to veg out and rest up before the fun begins tomorrow.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0526.jpeg" alt="twilight" /></p>

<p>We try to stay up a little later so we can adjust our internal clocks. We are all starting to doze around 7pm and head to bed a little after 8pm. We are all excited to hit the slopes tomorrow.</p>

<h2 id="day-3">Day 3</h2>
<h3 id="morzine--avoriaz">Morzine &amp; Avoriaz</h3>

<p>Today is our first day on the slopes. First things first though, we need a good breakfast. I head out to Les Epis du Roc to grab a baguette and some pastries while Orla makes eggs and bacon. The bread is so good.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0080.jpeg" alt="bakery" /></p>

<p>Morzine is a cute town built into the valley. It has some steep and winding streets and shortcuts for pedestrians.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0020.jpeg" alt="path" />
<img src="/assets/IMG_0021.jpeg" alt="village" /></p>

<p>After a fantastic breakfast we walk to Felix Ski to collect the skis and boots we rented yesterday.</p>

<p>Looks like another blue bird day</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0022.jpeg" alt="blue bird" /></p>

<p>We could just jump on the gondola at Pleany but we decide to head to Avoriaz instead. We hop on the bus A and we all get a seat. A few mins later we are boarding the cable car at Prodains that takes us up to Avoriaz.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0027.jpeg" alt="cable car" />
<img src="/assets/IMG_0028.jpeg" alt="pordains" /></p>

<p>We do a long run all the way back to the cable car and the conditions are great. Especially higher up. We decide to explore and after a great morning we stop for lunch at L’Alpage Du Crot (bottom right of photo).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0037.jpeg" alt="lunch" /></p>

<p>After a nice cold beer and and some food we head out again. This time we try the other side of Avoriaz and the conditions are even better. You can see the town of Morzine way in the background.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0041.jpeg" alt="top" /></p>

<p>What a fantastic day. We had read all about the snow shortages this season so our expectations we low but it was still amazing.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0045.jpeg" alt="seamus" /></p>

<p>We head over to the Swiss side of the ski area to see the Swiss wall. It is known as the most difficult run in Switzerland. Especially so this year I imagine with less powder. We take some photos and then head back to a hard black but no nearly as intimidating as Le Mur Swisse.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0057.jpeg" alt="ch" /></p>

<p>Séamus takes a nice photo of us overlooking the Swiss side.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0068.jpeg" alt="will and orla" /></p>

<h2 id="day-4--5">Day 4 &amp; 5</h2>
<h3 id="morzine--avoraiz">Morzine &amp; Avoraiz</h3>

<p>Today is a little warmer, in the mid 50s and sunny. Skiing in this weather is awesome. No need to wear too much and the breeze when moving is refreshing.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="615" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zae4HkqWXTM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Today we stop for lunch at Les Ancelles. It has a lot of good reviews for their Beef Bourguignon and it does not disappoint!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0095.jpeg" alt="lunch" /></p>

<p>After an awesome day on the slopes we head back to the apartment for a cup of tea and enjoy the view from our balcony.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0120.jpeg" alt="balcony" /></p>

<p>After relaxing for a couple of hours we decide to head into town for some food. We pass a WWI/WWII memorial in from of the church and wander around the quaint town.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0136.jpeg" alt="town" /></p>

<p>We grab a wonderful dinner at La Dez’Alp. The restaurant and the town have a real nice buzz and bustle going on.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0139.jpeg" alt="dinner" /></p>

<p>Back to Avoriaz today. It is a little colder and overcast. We are hoping that leads to snow at some point this evening, though the forecast is for rain.</p>

<p>We hit some of our favorite runs on the way to Mossettes, to do a few runs on the  Swiss side before lunch.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0595.jpeg" alt="border" /></p>

<p>Lunch today is at Cookie Cafe on the top of Mossettes. Though pricier than the French side it was delicious and has exceptional views.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0096.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>We head back to France for the remainder of our day. We are all starting to feel the wear and tear on our bodies after three epic days.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0143.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>The last run of the day was really tough. The fog came in and visibility was about 10’. We take our time to get below it and then enjoy the rest of the run. We were done anyway, our bodies are suffering at this point. Hoping for snow tonight.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="615" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JF-PLjBU0l0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="day-6--7">Day 6 &amp; 7</h2>
<h3 id="duck-duck-go">Duck Duck Go</h3>

<p>We went down to Châtel today. More awesome views (Orla and Séamus are the two on the right of photo).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0163.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>We have been waiting for tonight’s dinner since we booked it on Monday. Le Colin d’Oeil may be the best restaurant in Morzine.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0148.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>A Cosmo makes deciding which duck dish to get so much easier. The meal was superb and a nice cozy setting.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_0170.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>Séamus has been getting better and better all week. It has been hard to keep up with him. Luckily he likes to go off piste for jumps and things. It is the only thing keeping us close really. Check out the four videos of some of his jumps.</p>

<iframe width="740" height="455" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLWJYmxCCRpg6NDkWa1g_cKc-gR343reHe" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="day-8">Day 8</h2>
<h3 id="geneva">Geneva</h3>

<p>Returning from the Alps we like to spend a day in Geneva. This way we do not have to rush from our apartment to make our flight. We usually stay at the Ibis Budget at the PalExpo/Airport and our bus transfer drops at the airport.</p>

<p>After we checkin we hop on the local bus downtown</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1010.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>We walk along the lake and take in the sights. The tourist office is down by the lake and they have plenty of suggestions for you depending on how much time you have.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1009.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1013.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>We decide to walk along the lake to the botanical gardens</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1011.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>We noticed that the swans have started to work on their self-portraits</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1012.jpeg" alt="view" /></p>

<p>The gardens are nice and there is plenty blooming early in the season. It smells really great there too.
I noticed this odd structure on the bus ride in so I was glad to get back to get a better look.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1007.jpeg" alt="park" /></p>

<p>The small Japanese gardens has a koi pond and lovely plants.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1006.jpeg" alt="japanese" /></p>

<p>The Botanical Garden Greenhouse has a nice raised platform that allows you to walk around above some of the trees.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1005.jpeg" alt="tree" /></p>

<p>We then head toward the ICRC museum. On the way we pass the UN and the ‘Broken Chair’</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1004.jpeg" alt="broken chair" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1003.jpeg" alt="flags" /></p>

<p>The ICRC museum has three permanent exhibits and a temporary one. Defending Human Dignity and Restoring Family Links being the two standout ones for us.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1002.png" alt="cross" /></p>

<p>As a kid growing up in a christian country I had only ever heard it referred to the Red Cross. When I started to hear mention of the Red Crescent I had assumed this was a recent change. Turns out is has had the Red Crescent since 1876 which is pretty cool. The Red Crystal was introduced in 1992.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/IMG_1001.jpeg" alt="crystal" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="ski" /><category term="snowboard" /><category term="france" /><category term="switzerland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>